Jennifer Kiesler

Sun Prairie, WI

Phone: (262) 994-8243 | Email: kiesler.jen@gmail.com

GitHub: https://github.com/JenniferKiesler

Portfolio: https://jenniferkiesler.github.io/professional-portfolio/LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jennifer-kiesler-aa469591/

Summary

A Software Developer that has developed many applications independently and as part of a group. Have acquired many transferable skills from previous work experiences including problem-solving, communication, collaboration, ability to adapt to change, and time management.

Technical Skills

GitHub, Git, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, DOM, jQuery, Bootstrap, REST APIs, Agile, Node.js, OOP, TDD, Jest, Express.js, SQL, Postman, Heroku, Sequelize, MVC, Handlebars, NoSQL, PWA, React, GraphQL, MERN

Projects

House Rules

https://github.com/jonpfluger/house-rules.git | https://house-rules.herokuapp.com/

This application lets a user read posts about different types of games and write their own posts.

Tools: JavaScript, Express.js, Sequelize, Handlebars, Bootstrap, MVC, Anime.js, Cloudinary

Toss Me A Book

https://github.com/JenniferKiesler/toss-me-a-book.git | https://jenniferkiesler.github.io/toss-me-a-book/
This application helps the user find a book in many different ways including subject, title, author, or just have the application pick a book from the NYT best seller list that comes with a short description of the book.
Tools: HTML, CSS, Bulma, JavaScript, OpenLibrary API, Books API

Engineering Team Profile

https://github.com/JenniferKiesler/engineering-team-profile.git

https://drive.google.com/file/d/1 IJZwNghrA 7Wcx9lpxg7PLBd0dDaQ9O/view

A command-line application that takes in information about employees on a software engineering team and generates an HTML webpage that displays the information for each employee.

Tools: HTML, Bootstrap, Node.js, OOP, Inquirer, Jest

Education

University of Wisconsin Coding Bootcamp (Madison, WI)	Expected February 2023
Currently enrolled	
Certificate in Full Stack Web Development	
University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee (Milwaukee, WI)	May 2018
Biology and Chemistry Teaching Certifications	
University of Wisconsin-La Crosse (La Crosse, WI)	May 2014
Bachelor of Science (BS), Biology Major, Cellular/Molecular Emphasis, Chemistry Mir	nor

Professional Experience

Science Teacher, Marshall High School (Marshall, WI)

August 2020-June 2021

- Taught 90 students in the allotted time frame by planning ahead and being adaptable which allowed for more successful lessons
- Differentiated lessons by determining which methods would work best for each class/individual student which allowed for more students to be successful in the classroom
- Communicated with parents by email or phone to ensure all students were successful and parents were up to date on the student's progress

 Adapted to teaching remote and in-class students at the same time by creating more virtual activities for all students to do which allowed for all students to be able to learn

Science Teacher, Denmark High School (Denmark, WI)

August 2019-May 2020

- Created a new biology curriculum by collaborating with co-workers to meet the new standards students should learn to be successful outside of high school
- Instructed and presented information in a clear, concise way by using multiple different methods including visual and audio to increase student learning
- Adjusted successfully to teaching remotely by modifying lessons to work for virtual learning which allowed students to learn effectively outside of the classroom

Science Teacher, MC² High School (Milwaukee, WI)

August 2018-June 2019

- Developed the science department curriculum by organizing activities and units into a flowchart to make sure the different curriculums taught the students the standards required for that subject
- Ability to work under pressure by creating lesson plans for the week and to do lists which allowed everything to get done on time
- Analyzed the lessons by looking at the data and reflecting on how successful the lessons and activities were to determine whether the lesson worked or if the lesson needed to be adjusted and retaught

Research Associate, Aurora Health Care (Milwaukee, WI)

June 2016-June 2017

- Maintained a lab notebook by organizing the notebook by date and providing in depth details about what was done each day including the assays done and the results which made analyzing and comparing data easier
- Improved the methods for processing different tumor samples and maintaining tissue cultures which increased the success of the tissue cultures growing
- Wrote and maintained a tissue culture database by assessing tissue cultures already in storage and growing multiple tissue cultures for storage which improved the process to find tissue samples needed for experiments and increased the amount of samples available for research

Associate Research Specialist, UW - Madison (Madison, WI)

September 2015-April 2016

- Trained 2 graduate and 3 undergraduate students by teaching different lab techniques to help the lab run more efficiently
- Problem solved unexpected results by analyzing data and troubleshooting to be sure everything was done properly and results were accurate and repeatable